Guide to the Rice University Provost's Office Records: Neal Lane, 1986-1993 UA 121
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Rice University Provost's Office Records: Neal Lane
1986-93
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Lane, Neal F.
UA 121
19 Linear Feet (22 boxes)
These records reflect the daily business of the Provost's Office under physicist Dr. Neal Lane's leadership (1986-93). They reveal the daily business of the Provost's Office, which has the overall responsibility for the institution's educational and research programs.
Biographical / Historical
Neal Lane served as Provost of Rice University from 1986-1993. He joined the Rice Physics Department in 1966 and was made full professor in 1972. He was made chairman of the department in 1977. While chair, Lane spent 1979-80 serving as director of the division of physics at the NSF. He left Rice in 1984 to become Chancellor of the University of Colorado at Colorado Springs. He then returned to Rice to take on the job pf Provost.
In 1993, Lane was nominated by President Clinton as Director of the NSF and in 1998, he was nominated by President Clinton to be his new presidential science and technology advisor.
Dr. Lane, assistant to the president of the United States for science and technology, director of the U.S. Office of Science and Technology Policy, and former director of the national Science Foundation, rejoined the faculty at Rice University in Spring 2001.
Lane, a specialist in atomic physics, earned his undergraduate and graduate degrees, including his Ph.D., from the University of Oklahoma in the early 1960's.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of 22 boxes of Provost's Office records dating from physicist Dr. Neal Lane's tenure (1986-93). They reveal the daily business of the Provost's Office, which has the overall responsibility for the institution's educational and research programs. The Provost's Office is home to many interdepartmental initiatives and institutes, which fosters collaboration and innovative partnerships among faculty across disciplinary lines. These files share a similar file structure as that of the President's Office records.
The On Campus files (Series I and II) contain correspondence and documents pertaining to the academic and non-academic departments of the university such as the library, continuing studies, graduate office as well as correspondence relating to computing and ICSA. Also included are files relating to the Space Facilities Planning Board, Office of Sponsored Research, as well as faculty teaching evaluations and files from various campus organizations. Off Campus files (Series III) relate to university relationships with non-Rice groups and organizations.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Access Restrictions
Permission to access these records must be obtained from the Provost's Office. Form to request permission may be obtained from the Woodson Research Center.
Permission to use the records in four designated restricted boxes (19-22) must be obtained from the President's office. Form to request permission may be obtained from the Woodson Research Center.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Records were received from the Provost's Office in 6/1990, 7/1992, and in 1996. Most files were intermingled records from various Provosts between 1970 and 1993. Additional records were received received August 1994 and included four boxes which may only be opened with permission of the President. Some few records were included with boxes sent Aug. 25, 1989 for Provost Vandiver.
Related Materials
Information folder for Neal Lane, WRC
Records for Provost Dr. W.E. Gordon (1980-1985) and for Provost Dr. David Auston who followed Dr. Lane as Provost.
Index Terms
Subjects
Universities and colleges -- Administration; Universities and colleges
Document Types
letters (correspondence); notes; minutes (administrative records)
Subjects (Persons)
Lane, Neal F.; Lane, Neal F.
Subjects (Corporations)
Rice University. Office of the Provost; Rice University. Office of Sponsored Research.
- Series I: On Campus - General, 1986-93
  Scope and Contents note
  These files contain correspondence and documents pertaining to the academic and non-academic departments of the university such as the library, continuing studies, graduate office as well as correspondence relating to computing and ICSA. Also included are files relating to the Space Facilities Planning Board, Office of Sponsored Research, as well as faculty teaching evaluations and files from various campus organizations.
  - Academic Advising, 1986-90 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Academic Deans, 1987, 1992-93 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Administrative Computing, 1987, 1990 - Oct. 1991 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Administrative Computing, Nov. - Dec. 1991 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Administrative Computing, 1992-93 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Admissions Office, 1987-1992 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Affirmative Action, 1986-1987, 1990-92 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Air-conditioning, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Alumni Association, 1986-90 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Apple Consortium, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Budget, 1987-88 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Campus Business Office, 1986-88 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Class/Conference rooms, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Coherent Minors Program, 1986-89 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - (NEH proposal on) Coherent Minor, 1988-92 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - College courses, 1989, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Computer Science – Anthony Gorry, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - (Rice) Computing – Administration/PRIME, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - (Rice) Computing – Chemistry Department, 1986-87 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - (Rice) Computing – Directors, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - (Rice) Computing – HARC Supercomputer, 1986-87 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - (Rice) Computing – NSF-HAN proposal, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - (Rice) Computing – Physics, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Continuing Studies, 1986-87 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Continuing Studies, 1988-89 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Continuing Studies, 1990/91 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Continuing Studies, 1991/92 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Continuing Studies, 1992/93 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - (New) Curriculum, 1987-91 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Dean of Engineering Search Committee, 1986-88 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Dean of Engineering Search Active Folder, 1986-88, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Distribution courses, 1987-89, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Economic Summit, 1989-90 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - English for foreign graduate students, 1986-90 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - (VP for) External Affairs – Dove, 1986-88 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - (VP for) Financial Affairs – Glanville, 1986-87 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Foundation Courses, 1987-89 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Foundation Courses, 1990-91 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Foundation Courses – Humanities, 1988-92 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Foundation Courses – Natural Sciences (NCSI), 1988-92 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Foundation Courses – Social Sciences, 1988-89 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Foundation reporting on undergraduate curriculum, 1989-90 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Full-time Women Faculty, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - (Office of) Graduate Programs (Stout), Feb. - July 1986 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - (Office of) Graduate Programs (Stout), Aug. - Dec. 1986 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - (Office of) Graduate Programs (Stout), Jan. - May 1987 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - (Office of) Graduate Programs (Stout), June - Dec. 1987 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - (Office of) Graduate Programs (Glass), 1988-89 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - (Office of) Graduate Programs (Glass), 1990-91 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - (Office of) Graduate Programs (Glass), 1992-93 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - (Office of) Graduate Programs – Foreign Student Affairs, 1986-87 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - (Office of) Graduate Programs – Graduate Students, 1986-87 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - (Office of) Graduate Programs – Stipend/Tuition Budget, 1986-87 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Huxley Symposium/NEH proposal, 1986-87 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Institute for Computer Services and Applications (ICSA), 1986 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - ICSA, 1987-88, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - ICSA - Allocations, Administrative, 1986-87 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - ICSA – Allocations, Education, 1986-87 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - ICSA – Allocations, Research, 1986-87 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - ICSA – Computer Science Vax Bills, 1987-88 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - ICSA – External Affairs, 1986-87 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - ICSA – Networking, 1986-87 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - ICSA – Priscilla Huston/Farrell Gerbode Pending, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - ICSA – Revenues, 1986-87 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - ICSA – Revenues, AS 9000, 1986-87 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Institute of Biosciences and Bioengineering, 1986-90 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - (Fondren) Librarian Search Committee, 1989-90 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - (Fondren) Library – Carrington, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - (Fondren) Library – Carrington, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - (Fondren) Library – Carrington, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - (Fondren) Library – Carrington, 1989-90 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - (Fondren) Library – Patent Depository, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - (Fondren) Library – Personnel, 1987-90, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - (Fondren) Library – Ph.D. Programs, 1988, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - (Fondren) Library – Renovation, 1986-1988 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - (Fondren) Library – Shapiro, 1991-92 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Military Science/ROTC, 1986-87 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - (Office of) Networking and Computing, 1987, 1991-92 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - OWLNET, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - OWLNET, 1987-89 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - OWLNET, 1990-92 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Patent and Technology development, 1989 (Box 7A, Folder 1)
  - Permission to Publish, 1988 (Box 7A, Folder 2)
  - Pre-medical Scholars Program, 1986-89 (Box 7A, Folder 3)
  - Promotions, 1986-87 (Box 7A, Folder 4)
  - Publications Revolving Fund, 1987-89 (Box 7A, Folder 5)
  - Registrar, 1986-91 (Box 7A, Folder 6)
  - Rice-Baylor Cooperative, 1986, 1988-90 (Box 7A, Folder 7)
  - Rice Center for Education, 1993 (Box 7A, Folder 8)
  - Rice Design Alliance, 1987-92 (Box 7A, Folder 9)
  - Rice Engineering Design Development Institute (REDDI), 1986-88 (Box 7A, Folder 10)
  - Rice Institute for Policy Analysis (RIPA), 1986-90, 1992 (Box 7A, Folder 11)
  - Rice Quantum Institute, 1986-87 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Rice Quantum Institute, 1988-93 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Rice University Press, 1986-91, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Rice University School Mathematics Project (RUSMP), 1987, 1989-90, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Safety, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Scientia, 1986-92 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Sesquinet, 1986-88 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Space Facilities Planning Board (SFPB) - Brown School of Engineering Space Study Use, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - SFPB - C.I.S.I. Building Reponses, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - SFPB - Correspondence, 1986-87 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - SFPB - Correspondence, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - SFPB - Correspondence, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - SFPB - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - SFPB - Correspondence, 1991-92 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - SFPB - Correspondence, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - SFPB - Fall Fix 1900 Space Scenarios, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - SFPB - Gelco Space (Modular Buildings), 1988 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - SFPB - Herman Brown, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - SFPB - Humanities Social Studies, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - SFPB - Intermediate-Range Space Planning, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - SFPB - (Fondren) Library Committee Report, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - SFPB - (Fondren) Library Expansion Study, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - SFPB - Long-Range Space Planning, 1991-93 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - SFPB - Machine Room Meeting, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - SFPB - Master Plan for Growth – Cesar Pelli Assoc., 1983 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - SFPB - Meetings, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - SFPB - Meetings, Feb. June 1989 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - SFPB - Meetings, Aug. 1989 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - SFPB - Meetings, Nov. Dec. 1989 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - SFPB - Meetings, Jan. 1990 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - SFPB - Meetings, Feb. March 1990 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - SFPB - Meetings, Sept. Oct. 1990 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - SFPB - Meetings, Nov. 1990 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - SFPB - Meetings, Dec. 1990 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - SFPB - Meetings, Jan. Feb. 1991 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - SFPB - Meetings, March, April June 1991 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - SFPB - Meetings, Sept. Nov. 1991 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - SFPB - Meetings, Jan. March 1992 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - SFPB - Meetings, Aug. Nov. 1992 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - SFPB - Meetings, April Sept. 1993 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - SFPB - Music Building, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - SFPB - Music Building – Currie Analysis, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - SFPB - Physics Space Planning, 1988-89, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - SFPB - Projects, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - SFPB - Space Survey, An Analysis of Vacant Space, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - SFPB - Space Utilization Information, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - SFPB - Space Utilization Survey, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - SFPB - Statistics Move, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Summer School, 1986-91 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - (Office of) Sponsored Research (formerly Advanced Studies Research), Jan. 1986-May 1986 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - (Office of) Sponsored Research, June 1986 - Dec. 1986 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - (Office of) Sponsored Research, 1987-89 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - (Office of) Sponsored Research, 1990-92 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - (Office of) Sponsored Research, Personnel, 1986-87, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Teaching Evaluations, Fall 1986 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Teaching Evaluations, Spring 1986 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Teaching Evaluations, Fall 1987 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Teaching Evaluations, Spring 1987 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Teaching Evaluations – Correspondence, 1986-88 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Teaching Evaluations – Highs Lows, 1985-90 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Teaching Evaluations – Personnel, 1986-88 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Undergraduate Teaching by Tenured Faculty, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - VP Hayes, Ed – Associate Provost, 1987-90 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - VP Hayes, Ed – Correspondence, 1986-88 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - VP Hayes, Ed – Correspondence, 1989-92 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - VP Hayes, Ed – Discussions, 1991-92 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - VP Hayes, Ed – Information Systems, 1986-87, 1989, 1991, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - VP Hayes, Ed – Office of Sponsored Research, 1986-89 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - VP Hayes, Ed – Personal, 1986-87, 1990, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - VP Hayes, Ed – Search Committee, Associate Provost, 1986-87, 1989, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Series II: On Campus - Academic Units, 1986-93
  These files contain correspondence and documents that passed between the provost and the university academic departments and their deans.
  - Anthropology, 1987-91 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Architecture, 1986, 1988, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Architecture, Dean of - O. Jack Mitchell, 1986-89, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Architecture, Dean of - Paul Kennon, 1989-90 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Architecture, Dean of - Alan Balfour, 1989-90 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Architecture, Dean of - Alan Balfour, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Architecture, Dean of - Lars Lerup, 1992- (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Art Art History, 1987, 1989-91 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Biochemistry and Cell Biology, 1986, 1988-89, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Biochemistry and Biology – Life Sciences Visiting Committee, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Biology, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Biomedical Engineering, 1987-89 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Chemical Engineering, 1986, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Chemistry, 1987-90, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Civil Engineering, 1987, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Civil Engineering – Chair Search, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Computer Science, 1986-89, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Computer Science – Chair Search, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Ecology and Evolutional Biology, 1989, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Economics, 1986-88, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Education, 1987-91 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Electrical and Computer Engineering, 1986-89, 1991 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Engineering - Accreditation Board for Engineering and Technology (ABET), Self-Study Questionnaire for Review of Engineering Programs, Volume I, May 15, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - ABET, Volume II, Electrical Engineering, May 1987 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - ABET, Volume II, Materials Science Engineering, May 1987 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - ABET, Volume II, Mechanical Engineering, May 1987 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - ABET, Volume II, Chemical Engineering, May 1987 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - ABET, Volume II, Civil Engineering, May 1987 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - ABET Report, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - ABET Report, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Engineering – Budget, 1986 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Engineering, Dean of – J. D. Hellums, 1986 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Engineering, Dean of – J. D. Hellums, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Engineering, Dean of – J. D. Hellums, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Engineering, Dean of - Michael Carroll, 1992-93 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - English, 1987-88, 1990-93 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Environmental Science and Engineering, 1988, 1991-92 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - French and Italian, 1986-88, 1990-91 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Geology and Geophysics, 1986-89, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - German and Slavic Studies, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - History, 1986, 1990-92 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Human Performance and Health Sciences, 1986-87, 1989-91 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Humanities, 1990-91 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Humanities, Dean of – Allen Matusow, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Humanities, Dean of – Allen Matusow, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Humanities, Dean of - Meredith Skura, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Humanities, Dean of - Allen Matusow, 1992-93 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - (Jesse H.) Jones School of Administration – Center on the Management of Information Technology, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - (Jesse H.) Jones School of Administration – Council of Overseers, 1986-87, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - (Jesse H.) Jones School of Administration, Dean of – Doug Tuggle/B. Bailar, 1986-87, 1990, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Linguistics and Semiotics, 1987, 1989-90 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Mathematics, 1988, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Mechanical Engineering and Materials Science, 1986-87, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Natural Sciences, Dean of – G. K. Walters, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Natural Sciences, Dean of – G. K. Walters. 1987 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Natural Sciences, Dean of - James Kinsey, 1991-93 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Naval Science/R.O.T.C., 1987-88-91 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Physics, 1987-92 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Physics – Graduate Student Letters, 1987-88, 1991-92 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Political Science, 1990-91 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Psychology, 1987, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Religious Studies, 1991-92 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Shepherd School of Music, 1986, 1988, 1991-93 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Social Sciences, Dean of – Joseph Cooper, 1986-87 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Social Sciences, Dean of – Joseph Cooper, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Social Sciences, Dean of - James Pomerantz, 1992-93 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Sociology, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Space Physics and Astronomy, 1986, 1989-90 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Spanish/Portuguese/Classics, 1986-88, 1990-91 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Statistics, 1986-90 (Box 17, Folder 17)
- Series III: Off Campus - General, 1986-93
  These records contain correspondence and documents which passed between the provost and off campus groups and institutions. Foundation grant proposals, as well as correspondence with other universities, are found here.
  - Brown Foundation – Proposal for Center of Education, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Fund for the Improvement of Postsecondary Education (FIPSE), 1987, 1989-90 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - FIPSE – Project Director's meeting, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - FIPSE – Proposal and Progress Reports, 1989-92 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Foundations and Organizations – General, 1986-92 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - General Mills Foundation Grant for New Curriculum, 1988-89 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - (William and Flora) Hewlett Foundation, 1989-90 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Howard Hugh Medical Institute, 1988-90 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - International Correspondence, 1987-89, 1992 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Keck Foundation, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Mellon Grant Foundation Grant for Coherent Minor, 1987-88 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Pew Trust Proposal, 1988-89 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Sears Roebuck Foundation Proposal, 1988-89 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Texas Medical Center, 1986-89, 1992 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Universities, 1989-92 (Box 18, Folder 15)
- Series IV: Restricted Material
  Confidential / legal personnel files in sealed boxes labeled only with individual's names. These can only be used with the permission of the President.
  - unspecified (Box 19)
  - unspecified (Box 20)
  - unspecified (Box 22)
  - - (Box 21)